Saraba chikyuu yo, ai suru hito yo
Farewell Earth, and to the ones we love
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Chikyuu wo sukuu shimei o obite tatakau otoko
Men fight on a mission to save Earth
Moeru roman
It's a burning passion
Dareka ga kore wo yaraneba naranu
Someone has to do this
Kitai no hito ga ore tachi naraba
We are the trusted ones
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Earth Defense Force Headquarters
Gatlantis has been noticeably more active in the last few days.
Pluto, Neptune, the Asteroid Belt…
They appeared in various locations in the Solar System, engaged in battle, and withdrew temporarily.
Those must be diversions.
They're preparing for a
large-scale assault on Earth.
To confirm…
An object the size of Jupiter can warp ?
When will it reach the Solar System ?
Any chance of negotiation with them ?
Their objective is destruction.
It's apparent from the statements of the 11th planet
civilians currently being held in isolation on the Moon.
Gatlantis has no concept of expanding its
supremacy by conquering other civilizations.
If so…
War is unavoidable.
The factory in the time fault is operating at full capacity, but our forces are still inadequate.
Further collaboration between public and private sectors is necessary to strengthen our forces.
Earth Defense Force Reinforcement Unit
The wave motion gun fleet has drawn
criticism from both inside and outside, but…
…its value will be tested.
In the war against Garmillas,
we nearly went extinct.
Not this time around.
We don't have time. We must act now.
Otherwise mankind will…
Power to the CR booster system is confirmed.
Got it. We'll combine it with the
wave motion core booster.
The key to the survival of the human race…
We must complete it before those bastards arrive.
Warp complete.
Here it comes.
It's the data transmission from Earth.
Send it to the analyst immediately.
HQ must be tracking the White Comet's movements.
Aye, sir.
At this rate, we'll be able to talk to
them in real time in three days.
Relay all the family messages to the crew.
Aye, sir.
Good. It stabilized.
Captain, I'll go check the engine.
Please do.
We're really pushing it.
Warp should be limited to three times
a day, but that was the fifth one.
On top of that, the wave motion engine has
anti-wave motion photon "bacteria" inside it.
Lieutenant Keyman helped us,
but it wasn't so easy to remove…
Where's Keyman ?
In a confinement cell.
He returned to it himself afterwards.
Consecutive warps are hard on the injured, aren't they ?
You should go to sickbay,
but you came back here.
What a fool.
I'm a traitor.
You betrayed Desler, didn't you ?
Why didn't you go with him ?
I know about Desler.
He has the strength to ignore
the human side of mankind, like you.
It's the strength of killing one's self or others
without hesitation when deemed necessary.
That side of you…
For a moment, I heard my mother's voice.
I hadn't dreamed of her for so long.
But my mother didn't appear.
Instead, it was the Yamato's Yamamoto Akira.
Disappointed ?
No.
I was glad for some reason.
It might be fate as Teresa would put it.
Fate ?
Apparently, that's the connection between people.
Ties, love, whatever you call it…
…I feel like I've found it on this ship.
That's very human.
So irresponsible and selfish.
Love is the beginning of tragedy.
Tsubasa, your dad's job on
the Yamato will be over soon.
He's coming home.
You should ask him to
carry you on his shoulders.
He'll be surprised and say, "You grew so fast."
He's only two years old.
Please…
Because Nol also died in battle, we hastily materialized Gorland's succession clone.
We're about to hand him over to Zaizen,
the former Gorland, according to the rules.
Why are they smiling ?
Sir ?
It's just a mechanical procedure.
Why do they look like they're smiling ?
That's…
I don't know.
It seems to happen when we
see a life just being created.
Sometimes tears come down for some reason.
Apparently, Planet Telezart disappeared again.
Earth was the target of Teresa's cosmo wave.
But now that Telezart is gone…
It's only invisible to us.
Teresa is watching.
We'll invade Earth as planned.
To do that…
I'll arrange a new Silver Priestess as you wish.
Sabera is different from us Gatlantians.
Gatlantis was created by Zemulian.
She's a pure copy of one of them.
Unlike us clones, she doesn't
require a lengthy growth cycle.
She's very efficient, but…
…we need this size of memory device in order to re-create the body and soul of a human.
She's the Silver Maiden.
Only the last human is allowed to have such a luxury.
You said, as I wished, correct ?
Yes, in addition to the memory cap…
No issue with the suppression of emotions and
synchronization to the control device, I presume ?
It's thoroughly prepared.
A doll, huh ?
She shouldn't resonate with the
Sabera being held captive on the Yamato.
No suffering, either.
Garmillas has kept the policy of expanding its colonies for a long time, and it's undergoing a drastic change due to democratization.
However, our nation has a group of people who tried to turn the clock backward for autocracy.
The Garmillas National Security Police
hereby announces the arrest of all traitors.
Do you understand the meaning of arresting me ?
Only the Desler regime guarantees our future.
Nice and easy.
At this rate, Garmillas will be destroyed !
Shut up.
Prioritizing democratization before
dealing with the greater issue…
The path for your return to Garmillas is closed.
We can help you reclaim your authority if you wish…
…with one condition.
How dare you ?!
I do not wish to become a puppet of Gatlantis.
But you can save the decaying Garmillas.
You're pragmatic,
and different from your nephew.
Who are you ?
Here's the condition.
Destroy the Yamato.
Transit wave motion gun ?
Using the anti-wave motion photons as a booster, and mixing it with the wave motion gun.
If we can't remove it,
perhaps we can burn it completely ?
What would happen then ?
We can only use it once, but the energy released will be drastically increased…
…exponentially, I assume.
Any risks ?
Yes.
But I already have a solid idea of the
principle and mathematical formula.
The scar left by Keyman's betrayal
will become tremendous strength.
Could that be the power of fate
Teresa was talking about ?
That's too convenient.
I know, but the transit wave motion gun may
be our trump card to defeat the White Comet.
Mr. Sanada, you questioned why Gatlantis' Zorder wanted to obtain Teresa's power.
Yes.
It's just a hypothesis, but Teresa is a lifeform
who resides in a higher dimension.
She sees through time from the beginning to end.
If she descends into our universe, it might lose its variable nature and become rigid.
Huh ?
So, in other words…?
What's important is the phenomena, not theory.
What if our dimension loses the meaning of existence
due to the intervention of a higher dimensional lifeform ?
End of the universe…
But we met Teresa in person. That didn't…
We only saw her world through the Teresarium.
Our enemy's objective is…
…to exterminate all lifeforms including themselves.
That's what Zorder wants.
Saturn
Enceladus Defense Unit
More than one hundred
Calaklum class ships, and increasing !
The moment of truth…
Incoming message from Enceladus Defense Unit.
Patch it through.
This is the Enceladus Defense Unit.
Command HQ, do you copy ?
Increasingly large number of enemy ships detected in Saturn's orbit. Requesting immediate reinforcement.
I repeat. Number of enemy ships increasing. Requesting immediate reinforcement.
Communications lost.
Appears to be caused by the enemy ships' warp out.
Breaking through the center by taking
advantage of their overwhelming fleet size...
It's just as Ginga's AI predicted…
All carrier-borne aircraft have been
replaced with the Cosmo Tiger II.
No change of plans !
All ships, prepare to warp !
All ships, prepare to warp.
The Earth Federation has decided
to engage in war with Gatlantis.
Today's Earth Force is much better equipped than during the war against Garmillas.
They will protect Earth citizens' lives,
properties, and lands for sure.
That's what the wave motion gun fleet is for.
We can only depend on them for now.
The transit wave motion gun might be able to
blow away the White Comet's high pressure gas.
I'll make it in time.
More and more warp outs !
The Nazca class, and…
Unknown ship detected !
Put it on the main panel.
Look at the size…
That's their flagship ?
All aerial units, dive now !
Prepare to launch the Eaters.
Turn the catapult.
A number of small combat ships have been deployed by the large enemy battleship !
Small ships incoming !
Shoot them down !
Ship Eight's wave motion shield's been breached !
What ?
E23's destroyed !
How many are left ?
Six Kongo-class and eight escorts.
Intel says, many Calaklum class ships
are approaching from above !
What ?!
Calaklum ships destroyed !
Yamanami ?
You think you can win
with only that many ships ?!
Charge !
What a fool for being so overconfident in sheer power.
You should know that power can be
overwhelmed by an even greater power.
Lord Balsey, new enemy fleets appeared in the direction of Dagma, Bomie, and Zeven !
It's twice as large as before !
Where did Earth hide that many fleets…?
Balsey, a standstill in battle is unacceptable.
You do know that, don't you ?
Your Majesty !
It looks like I can have some fun.
Great Emperor…
Two more warps, and we'll be on the battlefield !
Make sure you're fully prepared !
Roger !
"There's a way to save your son."
"Ask Katsuragi Touko for details."
Take Inferno Canone formation !
Welcome…
…to hell.
Episode 17
Battle of Saturn - Gather the Wave Motion Gun Fleet !
Sotto oyasuminasai
A gentle goodnight
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Aihara Yoshikazu:
Ohta Kenjiro:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Niimi Kaoru:
Kiryu Mikage:
Yamazaki Susumu:
Kato Saburo:
Kato Makoto:
Kato Tsubasa:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Kokubun Masato
Chiba Yuki
Mugihito
Hisakawa Aya
Nakamura Eriko
Tsuchida Hiroshi
Hosoya Yoshimasa
Sato Rina
Takamori Natsumi
Osanago no youna toiki
You breathe like a little child
Saito Hajime:
Hijikata Ryu:
Yamanami Osamu:
Serizawa Kotetsu
Todo Saki:
Katsuragi Touko:
Abelt Desler:
Klaus Keyman:
Gharder Talan:
Loren Barrel:
Heidom Gimley:
Tochi Hiroki
Ishizuka Unsho
Ebara Masashi
Genda Tessho
Takagaki Ayahi
Kaida Yuko
Yamadera Koichi
Kamioya Hiroshi
Nakamura Kotaro
Terasoma Masaki
Morita Junpei
Itsumademo soba ni iru kara
I'll be by your side forever
Zorder:
Gailane:
Balsey:
Mill:
Vilho:
Factory Manger:
Nol (child):
Andromeda XO:
Andromeda Comm Man:
Andromeda Air Controller:
Dreadnaugut Crewman:
President:
Tezuka Hideaki
Shibata Hidekatsu
Nishimura Tomomichi
Uchiyama Koki
Tasaka Hiroki
Kikumoto Taira
Takebuchi Akira
Ichinose Hiroaki
Fujinuma Kento
Kamijo Tatsuya
Matsumoto Shinobu
Mikimoto Yuji
Mabuta tojite
So close your eyes
Hidamari no takeru youna yasashisa de...
As gentle as warm sunlight...
...Tsusumi komu yo
...I'll embrace you
Shiawase umidasu chikara
The power to bring happiness
Fuwari fuwari fuwa fuwa yume no naka
Drifting and floating, feeling like I'm having a dream
Omoi haseru yorisoinagara
Cuddling up and thinking of you from afar
Itsudemo waratte ite hoshii to negau
My wish is for you to keep on smiling
Never let your childlike smile disappear
Ubu na egao tayasanu youni
Itooshii hito yo...
My dearest one...
Preview
Crush them.
Destroy the Gatlantis stronghold.
What's that ?
How're we supposed to fight that ?
What the hell did you do ?!
Only parental love can save a child from dying.
Tsubasa, I'm sorry.
Episode 18
Yamato's Certain Death - Again, A Devil's Choice